Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Do you mean Gatlantis are like humans,
Chief Navigator Ichinose ?
It's based on how the battle opened at Saturn.
They're man made soldiers, who
aren't afraid of blowing themselves up.
The White Comet is a means of
destruction from ancient Archelias.
They use…
But they're taking the shape of humans.
Man made lifeforms should be able to
mechanize themselves for more efficiency.
All Inferno Canone ships are fully charged.
Wipe them out.
Damn them !
High energy signatures detected below the ring !
It's impossible.
Their planet was near dead
after their war with Garmillas.
How do they possess
such massive military power ?
You're embarrassing yourself, Balsey.
You must not turn around and withdraw
the fleet entrusted to you by His Majesty.
You are a Gatlantian. Die in battle.
Aye, sir.
This is amazing.
Where did you…?
Are you sure ?
It can cure the meteorite bomb syndrome ?
It should, although it was only
tested on some artificial cells.
So, it's curable…
Curable…
Can you use this sample to mass produce it ?
That's a different story.
When it comes to producing
this drug, I'm not sure.
Besides that, how did you get this ?
Hey !
Now, you know.
The drug can cure your child…
...and many others who suffer from the same illness.
The recipe is simple,
so it can be made on the ship.
It's just a matter of…
Who is it ?!
Who's helping you ?!
Tell me !
Go ahead. Kill me.
If I die, so does your child.
Why ?
Why're you doing this ?
With the power you guys have, you should be
able to destroy the Yamato and Earth so easily.
So, why ?
It's a game…
...a game of people tormented by love.
So, I'll keep my promise.
Otherwise, the game would be boring.
I see.
I've discovered the
gimmick that planet is using.
Time fault…
Sabera !
Gatlantis Empire, execute a phase transition jump.
Move aside, Balsey.
Your Majesty.
The White Comet has appeared.
It's estimated heading is Earth.
All ships, maintain gunnery formation, and pull back.
Proceed to Plan M.
Tsubasa…
According to the report from the Yamato, the core of the White Comet is estimated to be a planet-sized, man made fortress.
All fleets, take multi-tier formation.
Barrage and destroy the Gatlantis
stronghold hidden inside the comet !
Aren't you rushing this ?
The identity of the Comet
hasn't been discovered yet.
Ambassador Barrel, this is Earth's problem.
To prepare for the future negotiation,
we'll take another shot at the Comet.
Is that...
...your idea, Mr. President ?
Of course.
Deploy the graviton spread.
Fire !
All ships, prepare to fire wave motion guns.
The Comet is gaining speed.
Gravitational field conversion factor
has reached the planned value.
Target the core of the comet. Set 20-45.
Set 20-45. Synchronize the dispersion
wave motion guns to converge.
Energy charge, 120%.
Prepare for shock and flash.
Ten seconds to fire.
Nine...
...eight...
...seven...
...six...
...five...
...four...
...three...
...two...
...one…
Fire !
Did we do it ?
Crush them.
All ships, charge wave motion guns !
Wave motion guns, fire !
Gravitational downdraft strengthening !
Unable to slow down !
Turn around !
All ships, break away !
Wave motion gun barrels are heavily damaged !
We're being pulled in !
Engine output decreasing !
Contact with the Apollo Norm !
What ?
Commander Yamanami, please go.
The Apollo Norm is done for.
Captain Yasuda…
We'll push the Andromeda
with our remaining energy.
Yamanami, you did your best.
Yasuda…
Good luck.
What's that ?
That's Gatlantis ?
How're we supposed to fight that ?
Kodai…
…we'll bet on the transit wave motion gun.
Aye, sir.
Teresa said the power of fate that acts
between people will defeat the Comet Empire.
Let's trust her.
Fate brought us to this ship, and we're
going to engage in a decisive battle.
What gives power to fate
must be the will of each of us.
The people of Earth are not
willing to yield to their invasion.
We crawled out of the danger
of extinction three years ago.
Mankind will not back down.
We unite and fight until the end…
...in order to preserve freedom and peace...
...for the future of our children.
Only parental love can save a child from dying.
Isn't that right ?
It's incomparable love.
Selfish love.
Love that destroys everything.
What the hell have you done ?!
Tsubasa…
When Tsubasa was born,
I felt like I learned why I was born.
There are so many hardships in this world.
But still, he was born.
I guess it doesn't matter why...
…because I'm so glad to be
able to meet Sabu, and Tsubasa.
I don't need any reason for being happy.
Sorry…
…your dad will…
…go to hell.
What ?!
Chief, the output…
The wave motion engine has gone silent !
Oh, no. The anti-wave motion
photon's have gone out of control ?
We're entering the gravitational
field of the Comet Empire !
Episode 18
Yamato's Certain Death - Again, A Devil's Choice
Sotto oyasuminasai
A gentle goodnight
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Niimi Kaoru:
Kato Saburo:
Kato Makoto:
Kato Tsubasa:
Katsuragi Touko:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Hisakawa Aya
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Sato Rina
Takamori Natsumi
Kaida Yuko
Osanago no youna toiki
You breathe like a little child
Hijikata Ryu:
Yamanami Osamu:
Todo Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Todo Saki:
Ichinose Mina:
Yasuda Eijiro:
Ishizuka Unsho
Ebara Masashi
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Takagaki Ayahi
Kurosawa Tomoyo
Sasaki Isao
Itsumademo soba ni iru kara
I'll be by your side forever
Klaus Keyman:
Loren Barrel:
Zorder:
Sabera:
Gailane:
Balsey:
Genitz:
Vilho:
Andromeda XO:
Andromeda Comm Man:
Andromeda Air Controller:
President:
Kamioya Hiroshi
Terasoma Masaki
Tezuka Hideaki
Kaida Yuko
Shibata Hidekatsu
Nishimura Tomomichi
Hideyuki Umetsu
Hiroki Tasaka
Ichinose Hiroaki
Fujinuma Kento
Kamijo Tatsuya
Mikimoto Yuji
Mabuta tojite
So close your eyes
Hidamari no takeru youna yasashisa de...
As gentle as warm sunlight...
...Tsusumi komu yo
...I'll embrace you
Shiawase umidasu chikara
The power to bring happiness
Fuwari fuwari fuwa fuwa yume no naka
Drifting and floating, feeling like I'm having a dream
Omoi haseru yorisoinagara
Cuddling up and thinking of you from afar
Itsudemo waratte ite hoshii to negau
My wish is for you to keep on smiling
Never let your childlike smile disappear
Ubu na egao tayasanu youni
Itooshii hito yo...
My dearest one...
Preview
I won't let you get through...
...Gatlantis !
Ginga
Episode 19
Yamato's Successor Bears the Name of Ginga